Guide to Robert H. Ledyard Collection
Erie Canal Museum
Robert H. Ledyard Collection
1850 - 1892
Correspondence and other materials relating to the usage of Cazenovia Lake and its outlets to feed the Erie Canal.
1 box
Ledyard, Robert H.
Erie Canal Museum 318 Erie Boulevard East Syracuse, NY 13202
The Collection is open for research use.
Jonathan D. Ledyard was responsible for the management of the waters of Cazenovia Lake and the Erieville Reservoir. Collection donated by Robert H. Ledyard.
Cazenovia Lake (N.Y.); Erie Canal (N.Y.); Chittenango Creek (N.Y.)
Correspondence and Agreements relating to the use of Cazenovia Lake and Chittenango Creek to feed the Erie Canal.
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence-Water Management, Cazenovia Lake, 1881
    - Correspondence-Dec. 1881, December, 1881; Includes items 76.1219.6-.10 (Box 1, Folder Correspondence-Dec. 1881)
    - Correspondence-1855-1868, Includes items 76.1221-.1222.30 (Box 1, Folder Correspondence-1855-1868)
    - Correspondence-1875-1892, Includes items 76.1223,.1224,.1226 A+B, .1228 (Box 1, Folder Miscellaneous-Materials relating to Cazenovia Lake, 1853-1892)
    - Correspondence-Sewage Drain in Cazenovia, 1887, Includes items 76.1232.1-.20 (Box 1, Folder Correspondence-Sewage Drain in Cazenovia, 1887)
    - Correspondence-1866-1881, Includes items 76.1234.1-.7 (Box 1, Folder Correspondence-Water Management, Cazenovia, 1866-1881)
    - Correspondence-1857-1869, Includes items 76.1239.1-.20 (Box 1, Folder Correspondence-Canal Management, 1857-1869)
    - Correspondence-1869, Includes items 76.1240.1-.21 (Box 1, Folder Correspondence-Water Management, 1869)
- Legal Documents
  - Claims
    - Legal Claim-R. Parsons, 1855, October 13, 1855; Includes items 76.1217-.1218 (Box 1, Folder Legal Claim-R. Parsons, 1855)
  - Agreements
    - Agreement-Stephen Chapke, 1875, Includes item 76.1225; Stephen F. Chapke, signed agreement releasing state of any damages in relation to using Cazenovia Lake as a reservoir for the Erie Canal (Box 1, Folder Miscellaneous-Materials relating to Cazenovia Lake, 1853-1892)
    - Agreement-Reuben Parsons, Stephen Chapke, 1853, Agreement to divide gristmill property; Includes item 76.1227 (Box 1, Folder Miscellaneous-Materials relating to Cazenovia Lake, 1853-1892)
    - Agreement-Reuben Parsons, 1873, Statement by Reuben Parsons giving New York State land to build a new dam on in Cazenovia; Includes item 76.1229 (Box 1, Folder Miscellaneous-Materials relating to Cazenovia Lake, 1853-1892)
    - Agreement-Land Owners, State of New York, 1873, Agreement by land owners on Chittenango Creek and Cazenovia Lake, for state to build new dam and releasing state from any claim of damages involved in the construction.; Includes items 76.1230-.1231 (Box 1, Folder Miscellaneous-Materials relating to Cazenovia Lake, 1853-1892)
    - Agreements Relating to Dam on Cazenovia Lake Outlet, 1873; Includes items 76.1235-.1237 (Box 1, Folder Documents relating to dam on Cazenovia Lake Outlet)
    - Agreements-Water Usage, Cazenovia Lake, Includes items 76.1241-.1243 (Box 1, Folder Agreements-Water Usage, Cazenovia Lake)
- Newspaper Articles
  - News Articles, undated
    - Newspaper Articles-Cazenovia Lake, Four copies of article about water usage and regulations for Cazenovia Lake. One article detailing proceedings of canal board.; Includes items 76.1219.1-.5 (Box 1, Folder Newspaper Articles-Cazenovia Lake)
- Miscellaneous
  - Water Usage-Cazenovia Lake
    - Documents Relating to Water Usage on Cazenovia Lake, 1850-1877, Correspondence, reports, and agreements relating to water usage on Cazenovia Lake and outlets.; Includes items 76.1238.1-.25 (Box 1, Folder Documents Relating to Water Usage on Cazenovia Lake, 1850-1877)
- Reports
  - Reports, 1881
    - Report-History of Water Rights on Cazenovia Lake, 1881, Includes item 76.1216 (Box 1, Folder Report-History of Water Rights on Cazenovia Lake, 1881)
    - Report-History of State Connection with Chittenango Creek, 1881, Includes item 76.1233 (Box 1, Folder Report-History of State Connection with Chittenango Creek, 1881)
  - Reports, 1873
    - Report-Usage of Cazenovia Lake, 1873, August 7, 1873; Includes item 76.1220 (Box 1, Folder Report-Usage of Cazenovia Lake, 1873)